+234 81 6136 1936 hi@efeojadua.dev FCT Abuja, Nigeria

Github LinkedIn

Profile

Efe Ojadua is a versatile Product Designer and Developer with over 7 years of experience. He holds a BSc in Accounting but forged his path as a self-taught developer. Efe's expertise spans UI/UX design, frontend and backend development, and a comprehensive skill set that includes Figma, Adobe Illustrator, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React Js, Svelte, Tailwind CSS, Redux, GraphQL, Golang, Python, and Relational Databases.

Experience

Lead Frontend Developer - Travvelbaby

December 2020 - January 2022

Efe took the reins of frontend development at Travvelbaby, a venturebacked social platform focused on fundraising for leisure travels and;

- Built and maintained the platform's front-end using React Js, Redux, and Tailwind CSS
- Worked closely with the founders to design and implement highfidelity designs
- Optimized the platform's performance and scalability

Co-Founder & CTO - Middletrust

May 2019 - July 2021

Co-founded and led the development of an innovative fintech app.

- · Oversaw all aspects of product development, from ideation to launch
- Spearheaded product design and development, ensuring a seamless user experience.
- Managed a dynamic team, driving innovation and technical
- Maintained the startup's web applications using React Js, Express JS, and Postgres, actively adding new features and debugging arising issues.

Freelance Frontend Developer

June 2015 - Present

- Collaborated with notable brands such as Oracle, Test-Ace, Rentvec, Wecanrush, Metamars, Quadplan and more.
- Designed and developed tailored solutions, contributing to their digital success.

Certifications

→ AWS Cloud Practitioner

Key Strengths

UI/UX Design

React JS

React Native

Svelte

Redux

Jest

SASS

Tailwind CSS

GraphQL

Python

Golang

Relational Databases

Other Strengths

Collaborative Team Player

Fast Learner

Agile Development

Critical Thinker

Hobbies

- Mentoring
- Traveling
- Photography
- Creative Writing
- Leisure Coding
- Designing

Education

Languages

English (Fluent)

Bachelors of Science - Accounting

2010 - 2014 · University of Benin, Benin City

After satisfying the necessary institutional requirements, Efe was awarded a Bachelors of Science in Accounting.

Career Path Diploma - Frontend Development

2023 · Codecademy

After satisfying the necessary institutional requirements, Efe was awarded a diploma in Frontend Development.

Advanced Diploma - Computer Science

2023 · Codecademy

After satisfying the necessary institutional requirements, Efe was awarded a diploma in Computer Science.

Referees

Elo Hankham

Co-Founder/CEO - Travvelbaby (USA) - Elohankham@travvelbaby.com

Jordan LaPalm

CEO - Test-Ace (USA) - testextraodinaire@gmail.com

Paul Aileku

CEO - Wecanrush Inc (USA) - paulaileku@wecanrush.com